A Finding Aid to the Elizabeth McCausland Papers, 1838-1995, bulk 1920-1960, in the Archives of American Art AAA.mccaeliz
Archives of American Art
- Marsden Hartley, bulk 1944-1964; 1900-1964; Series 6; 10 Linear feet Boxes 11-21, OV 37
  - Card Files, circa 1944-1964; 6.3
    - Index to Titles of Marsden Hartley Works, circa 1944-1964 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Index to Marsden Hartley Correspondence, circa 1944-1964 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Index to Marsden Hartley Exhibitions, circa 1944-1964 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Index to Owners of Marsden Hartley Works, circa 1944-1964 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Index to Events in Life of Marsden Hartley, circa 1944-1964 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence and General Files, bulk 1950-1964; 1900-1964; 6.4
    Subseries consists of correspondence and other files concerning more technical or business-related aspects of McCausland's research, including requests for information, business arrangements with University of Minnesota, permissions, etc. Correspondence also concerns research on Hartley's time in Garmisch-Partenkirchen and aspects of his life and work (including his relationship and correspondence with Rebecca S. James); the Hartley exhibition organized by the Stedelijk Museum Amsterdam and American Federation of Arts (1960-1962); the Life Magazine article on Hartley, as well as several articles by McCausland (including a reprint of a speech on Hartley published in Art in America and a piece entitled, "A Field Trip in Hartley Country," for which she sought a publisher); and McCausland's consulting on Hartley forgeries. Files also include original letters from Hartley to Richard Tweedy, 1900-1901 (which were given to the American Art Research Council at the Whitney Museum of American Art in 1945, and subsequently turned over to Elizabeth McCausland), Hudson Walker, 1937-1943, and Johann Langaard, 1939; typescripts of Hartley’s letters to Mathilde Rice, Hudson Walker, and Ione Walker; and typescript excerpts of Hartley's letters to unidentified recipients.
    Related correspondence can also be found amongst general correspondence. Files are arranged in alphabetical order.
    Almost all of the material in this subseries has been scanned, except for duplicate materials and the photographs of works of art. Only the cover and title pages for a few of the publications have been scanned.
    - A, 1953-1961 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - B, 1950-1952, 1959-1962 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Bibliography, 1937-1954 (Box 16, Folder 23-24)
    - D, 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - E, 1951, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Typescript Excerpts from Marsden Hartley Letters, circa 1917-1938 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - F, 1951, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - "A Field Trip in the Hartley Country" (1960), 1962 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Forgeries, 1961-1963 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - G, 1950, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Gallup, Donald (Yale University Library), 1952, 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - H, 1951-1960 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Haering, Ilene (re: Garmisch-Partenkirchen), 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 34-35)
    - Hartley, Marsden (Box 16)
      - Typescripts of Letters to Mathilde Rice, circa 1925-1928 (Box 16, Folder 36)
      - Letters to Richard Tweedy, 1900-1901 (Box 16, Folder 37-38)
      - Typescripts of Letters and Letters to Hudson Walker, circa 1935-1942 (Box 16, Folder 39-43)
        Also includes a letter from Hartley to Johann Langaard, 1939.
      - Typescripts of Letters to Hudson Walker, circa 1939-1941 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
        Also included is a typescript of a letter to Ione Walker, 1940.
    - Hartley and Stieglitz, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Isaacson, Philip, 1960-1962 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - I-J, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - James, Rebecca S., 1951-1954 (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
    - K, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Kuntz, Adelaide, 1951-1953 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - L, 1951, 1960-1961 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Life Magazine, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Lipman, Jean ( Art in America), 1947, 1952-1953, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 12-13)
    - Lowenthal, Mr. and Mrs. Milton, 1952-1953 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - M, 1951-1960 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Marsden Hartley Estate, 1952, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - N, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - New York Public Library, circa 1950-1964 (Box 17, Folder 18-19)
    - O, 1958, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - P, 1951-1953, 1960-1961 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Permission, 1959-1960 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, 1962-1963 (Box 17, Folder 23-26)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, Correspondence, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Portraits of Marsden Hartley, circa 1950-1964 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Printed Material, 1961-1964 (Box 17, Folder 29-30)
    - Progress Report, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - R, 1951-1960 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Research Notes, 1960-1962 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - S, 1951-1952 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Sprinchorn, Carl, 1951-1962 (Box 17, Folder 35)
    - Stedelijk Museum Amsterdam, 1960-1962 (Box 17, Folder 36-37)
    - T, 1953-1962 (Box 17, Folder 38)
    - U, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 39)
    - University of Minnesota (Box 17)
      - Arnason, H. Harvard, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 40)
      - Contracts, 1951-1963 (Box 17, Folder 41)
      - Miscellaneous, 1945, 1951-1952, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 42)
      - Slides, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 43)
      - University Gallery, 1951-1953, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 44-45)
      - University Press, 1951-1953 (Box 17, Folder 46-49)
      - Wiley, Malcolm, 1950-1964 (Box 17, Folder 50-51)
    - University of Nebraska, 1960, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 52)
    - University of Texas, 1961-1963 (Box 17, Folder 53)
    - V, 1960-1961 (Box 17, Folder 54)
    - W, 1950-1961 (Box 17, Folder 55)
    - Walker, Hudson (Box 17)
      - Correspondence, 1950-1961 (Box 17, Folder 56)
      - "Marsden Hartley, The Painter", circa 1950-1964 (Box 17, Folder 57)
      - "Borrowed from HDW (Hudson D. Walker) personal file Hartley", 1943-1951 (Box 17, Folder 58-60)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1947, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 61)
    - Worcester Art Museum, 1954, 1959-1960 (Box 17, Folder 62)
    - Yale University Art Gallery, 1950, 1953, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - Other Research Files, bulk 1944-1962; 1921-1962; 6.5
    Files found here substantively relate to McCausland's research on Hartley. Included are files on a Hartley bibliography that include writings by others about Hartley and copies of Hartley's correspondence from other research repositories. There are also files on various research topics, such as chronology and exhibitions, Hartley correspondence, dating and style of Hartley works, and iconography of Hartley's "Military Series"; research forms for the Hartley paintings in the Hudson Walker Collection on long-term loan to the University of Minnesota; and various "working" files of unsorted material meant to be entered on forms, filed, or returned. Files also include photographs of works of art (many not scanned); writings, including a piece on Georgia O'Keeffe and possibly other scattered writings by Hartley and a piece "Hartley Fragments" by McCausland; and some notes on the manuscript of the biography.
    This subseries has been scanned in its entirety, except for photostat copies of material from other repositories, duplicates, photographs of works of art, entire issues of magazines, and slides. In addition, only the covers, title pages, and relevant pages from many of the publications have been scanned.
    - Alfred Stieglitz Correspondence (copied from Yale University Library), 1950s (Box 17, Folder 64)
    - Armory Show, 1937-1938, 1946, 1950s (Box 17, Folder 65-67)
    - Bibliography, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 68)
    - Bibliography Research (Box 17)
      - Period of 1877-1922, [1950s] (Box 17, Folder 69)
      - Period of 1923-1929, [1950s] (Box 17, Folder 70)
      - Period of 1930-1934, [1950s] (Box 17, Folder 71)
      - Period of 1937, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Period of 1938, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Period of 1939, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Period of 1940, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Period of 1941, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Period of 1942, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Period of 1943, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Period of 1944, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Period of 1945, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Period of 1946, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Period of 1947, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Period of 1948, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Period of 1949-1951, [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Period of 1952, 1950s (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Period of 1953, 1950s (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous, 1952-1960 (Box 18, Folder 16-18)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 19-20)
      - New York Public Library, circa 1944-1962 (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - On Microfilm, circa 1944-1962 (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Chronology and Exhibitions (Notebook for Card Index Files), circa 1944-1962 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Exhibitions, 1921, 1944-1962 (Box 18, Folder 24-25)
    - Hartley Catalog, 1951-1954 (Box 18, Folder 26-27)
    - Jacques Lipchitz Correspondence, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Microfilm, Marsden Hartley Correspondence (1928-1942), circa 1945 (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - Notes, circa 1944-1962 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Notes, W. Joseph Fulton, circa 1944-1962 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Notes, "Study for People", 1953 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Notes, Things to Do (?), 1951-1953 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Notes on Dating and Style, 1950-1953 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Notes on Iconography of Hartley's "Military Series", [1950s] (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Notes on Manuscript of Biography, Chapters 2-3, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Photographs of Hartley Works Held by Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, 1953-1959 (Box 18, Folder 40)
    - Photographs of Works of Art, Various Artists, circa 1944-1962 (Box 18, Folder 41)
    - Prices of Hartley Paintings, 1940-1944 (Box 18, Folder 42)
    - Printed Material, Magazines, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Printed Material, Magazines, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 44)
    - Problems, circa 1944-1962 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "Problems and Methods of Study," Notes on Lecture, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Research Forms, circa 1944-1962 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Rosenberg, 1944-1952 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
    - Slides, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Tabulation of Art Work, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - To Be Entered on Forms, 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 8-10)
    - To Be Filed (Box 19)
      - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Notes on Marsden Hartley Correspondence, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Research Material, 1951-1958 (Box 19, Folder 13-15)
    - To Be Returned, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Unfinished Business (American Art Research Council), 1945-1950, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 17-18)
    - "The University Set of Research Forms of the Hartleys in the Collection of Mr. and Mrs. Hudson Walker", 1951, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Writing by Hartley, "Georgia O'Keeffe", circa 1944-1962 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Writings by Hartley (?), circa 1944-1962 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Writing by McCausland, "Hartley Fragments", circa 1944-1962 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Interviews, 1959-1960; 6.6
    Subseries consists of tapes and transcripts of two interviews about Marsden Hartley. One is a discussion of the artist by Hudson Walker, McCausland, and Mary Bartlett Cowdrey conducted on February 2, 1959. The other is an interview of the artist Jacques Lipchitz by McCausland and Cowdrey about his friendship with Hartley, conducted on February 20, 1960.
    Transcripts in this subseries have been scanned.
    - Marsden Hartley Discussed by Hudson Walker, Elizabeth McCausland, and Mary Bartlett Cowdrey (Box 19)
      - Reel-to-Reel Tapes, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 23-27)
      - Transcripts, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 28-30)
    - Jacques Lipchitz Interviewed by Elizabeth McCausland and Mary Bartlett Cowdrey (Box 19)
      - Reel-to-Reel Tape, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 31)
        See Box 19, Folder 27
      - Transcripts, 1960 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Auction Catalogs, bulk 1905-1929; 1905-1963; 6.7
    Subseries consists of numerous auction catalogs dating from 1905 to 1929, with some scattered auction catalogs from 1937 to 1939 and from 1961 and 1963. It is unclear how these relate to Marsden Hartley or McCausland's Hartley study.
    Auction catalogs are arranged in chronological order.
    - Auction Catalogs, 1905 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1906 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1907 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1908 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1910 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1911 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1912 (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1913 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1914 (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1915 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1916 (Box 20, Folder 10-12)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 13-16)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 17-18)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1919 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1921 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1923 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1924 (Box 21, Folder 5-8)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 9-11)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Auction Catalogs, 1961, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Auction Catalogs, circa 1905-1963 (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Other Research and Writing Files, 1896, 1926-1958; Series 7; 4.6 Linear feet Boxes 21-25, 31
  Series consists of files relating to McCausland's other research projects, which produced a more limited amount of documentation, including projects on the painters E. L. Henry and George Inness, and the photographer Lewis Hine, as well as various smaller and perhaps less well-defined projects on different art topics.
  The series is arranged as 4 subseries:
  7.1: E. L. Henry, 1940-1946
  7.2: Lewis Hine, 1938-1942
  7.3: George Inness, 1935-1936, 1944-1946
  7.4: Various Projects, 1896, 1926-1958
  This series has been scanned in its entirety, except for duplicates. In many cases, only the cover, title page, and relevant pages of publications have been scanned.
  - E. L. Henry, 1940-1946; 7.1
    Subseries consists of files relating to McCausland's research for the exhibition, "E. L. Henry Collection" (New York State Museum, 1942), which she organized, and her book, The Life and Work of Edward Lamson Henry, N. A., 1841-1919, which was first published in 1945 as New York State Museum Bulletin number 339. Files include correspondence (primarily with Charles Adams, Director of the New York State Museum), notes on the chronology of Henry's life and his sketchbooks, material related to expenses for work carried out, and some installation photographs of the exhibition.
    - Chronology, [1941-1942] (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Clippings, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 21-25)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 21, Folder 26-28)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Exhibition Catalog, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Expenses, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
    - Expenses, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Expenses, 1943 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Installation Photographs of E. L. Henry Exhibition (1942), 1946 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Notes on Sketchbooks, [1941-1942] (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Photographs in Album Listed Serially, [1941-1942] (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Lewis Hine, 1938-1942; 7.2
    Subseries consists of files relating to McCausland's "rediscovery" of the pioneer documentary photographer Lewis Hine, and her research for the retrospective exhibition of his work that she organized for the Riverside Museum in 1939 and for various articles on the artist, including one published in U.S. Camera (1939). Files include correspondence (including correspondence with Hine), notes, manuscripts, prints of Hine photographs, and some photographs of Hine taken by Berenice Abbott.
    - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 22, Folder 15-16)
    - Exhibition at Riverside Museum, 1938-1939 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Manuscripts and Published Articles, 1938 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Notes and Research Material, 1938-1942 (Box 22, Folder 19-22)
    - Photographs as Art (Box 22)
      - Ellis Island, circa 1938-1942 (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - Child Labor, circa 1938-1942 (Box 22, Folder 24)
      - Men at Work, circa 1938-1942 (Box 22, Folder 25)
      - New York City Scenes, circa 1938-1942 (Box 22, Folder 26)
      - Steel Workers, circa 1938-1942 (Box 22, Folder 27)
      - Chicago and Other Places, circa 1938-1942 (Box 22, Folder 28)
      - Untitled, circa 1938-1942 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Photographs of Lewis Hine (photographer: Berenice Abbott), 1939 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - George Inness, 1935-1936, 1944-1946; 7.3
    Subseries consists of files relating to McCausland's research for the exhibition, "George Inness: An American Landscape Painter, 1825-1894," organized for the George Walter Vincent Smith Art Museum in 1946 (also shown at the Brooklyn Museum and Montclair Art Museum), and for her book of the same title, published by American Artist Group the same year. Files include correspondence, catalog material, notes, and reference material. Some correspondence concerns inquiries fielded by McCausland seeking her expertise on Inness paintings.
    - Bibliography, 1935-1936, 1944-1945 (Box 22, Folder 31-32)
    - Book Cover, [1946] (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Catalog Data, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, Pond, Cordelia Sargent Pond (George Walter Vincent Smith Art Museum), 1945-1946 (Box 22, Folder 35-38)
    - Correspondence, Others, 1945-1946 (Box 22, Folder 39-41)
    - Definitive Catalog, [1945-1946] (Box 22, Folder 42-44)
    - Lacunae - Frick Collection, New York Public Library, [1945] (Box 22, Folder 45-46)
    - "New Leads", 1945-1946 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Photostats, [1945] (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Transcription of Letter from George Inness, circa 1944-1946 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Various Projects, 1896, 1926-1958; 7.4
    Subseries consists of files stemming from various research projects, some of which resulted in a finished product (such as articles, books, other published works) and some of which were only planned and never completed, and other research activities, such as speaking engagements and consulting jobs. Files include correspondence, notes, manuscripts, proofs, project proposals, contracts and agreements, call slips, questionnaires, reports, and printed material.
    Found are files relating to articles and writings on artists, Arthur Dove, Martin Johnson Heade, Robert Henri, and Jacob Lawrence, among others; on film and photography, including numerous articles for The Complete Photographer, Minicam Photography, Modern Photography, and Photography; her work with Berenice Abbott; and on more general topics, such as "Art and Advertising" and "Why Can't Americans Afford Art?".
    There are also files relating to McCausland's published book, Careers in Art (1950); to her work on a selected bibliography on American art, which appeared in Magazine of Art (1946); to her catalog for the Charles Hawthorne exhibition at the Grand Central Art Galleries in 1947; to speaking engagements at the American Artists Congress Symposium in 1940 and the National Convention of the American Association of University Women in 1947; to her applications for Guggenheim fellowships; and to various planned projects, including her long-term study on the artist in America from 1641 to 1941 and her study of the nude in American art.
    Also found are files relating to various freelance consulting and editing jobs, including photo-editing Carl Sandburg's book of poems, Poems of the Midwest, assisting as special publications editor for the opening of the Everyday Art Gallery at the Walker Art Center, and conducting a survey of art education for Cooper Union Art School.
    - Abbott, Berenice, "Metropolis: Old and New" and Other Projects, 1954 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - American Art History (Box 23)
      - Clippings, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Notes, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 7-8)
    - American Artists Congress Symposium, 1939-1940 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - American Association of University Women, National Convention, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 10-12)
    - American Dance Association, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Article on Elizabeth McCausland, circa 1951 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - The Artist in America, 1641-1941, circa 1944 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Bibliography, 1946-1947 (Box 23, Folder 16-21)
    - Bibliography, Sources, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 22-28)
    - Card Index Files (Box 23)
      - Alphabetical, circa 1926-1958 (Box 23, Folder 29)
        See Box 31
      - Index to Clippings, circa 1926-1958 (Box 23, Folder 30)
      - "Social Matrix", circa 1926-1958 (Box 23, Folder 31)
      - Subject I, circa 1926-1958 (Box 23, Folder 32)
      - Subject II, circa 1926-1958 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Careers in the Arts (Box 23)
      - Bibliography, 1946-1950 (Box 23, Folder 34-35)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950-1953 (Box 23, Folder 36)
      - Notes, 1948-1950 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - The Complete Photographer (Willard D. Morgan), 1940-1942 (Box 23, Folder 38-39)
    - Cooper Union Art School Survey, 1948-1949 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Dickinson, Emily, 1929-1933 (Box 24, Folder 2-3)
    - "The Dilemma of Culture", circa 1926-1958 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - "Documenting Changing New York", 1939 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Dove, Arthur G. (Box 24)
      - Article, "Dove: Man and Painter", 1896, 1930-1937, 1941 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Critical Study, circa 1926-1958 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Proposed Critical Biography, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 8-9)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, Patronage, circa 1926-1958 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Film, "Art and Pinocchio", circa 1926-1958 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Guggenheim Fellowship (Box 24)
      - Applications, 1935-1942 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence (See also General Correspondence), 1951, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Hawthorne, Charles W., 1947-1948 (Box 24, Folder 14-16)
    - Heade, Martin Johnson, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 17-18)
    - Henri, Robert (Box 24)
      - Bibliography, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence and Contract, 1956-1958 (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - Notes, [1957] (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - Notes on Sketchbooks, [1957] (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - "History of Photography", 1926, 1941, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 23-25)
    - "How Artists Work"(?), Graphic Art, 1935 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - "How Artists Work," Manuscript, circa 1935 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Index of American Design, 1938, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Kiesler, Frederick J., circa 1926-1958 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Kollwitz, Kaethe, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 30-31)
    - Kollwitz Portfolio, 1941-1942 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Lawrence, Jacob, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Minicam Photography (Will Lane), 1941-1942 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Modern Photography, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 36-43)
    - Morse, Samuel F. B., undated (Box 24, Folder 44-45)
    - National Art Week, 1941 (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous, 1935 (Box 24, Folder 47)